<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>iCodeX's blog</title><subtitle>icodeX's daily journey of coding, problem-solving, and sharing insights from real-world projects.</subtitle> <updated>2025-03-21T12:19:32-04:00</updated> <author> <name>icodex-s24</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2025 icodex-s24 </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Building a Docker Environment Completely Offline on Windows 10</title><link href="/posts/how-use-docker-windows-offline/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Docker Environment Completely Offline on Windows 10" /><published>2024-11-20T20:52:36-05:00</published> <updated>2024-11-20T20:52:36-05:00</updated> <id>/posts/how-use-docker-windows-offline/</id> <content src="/posts/how-use-docker-windows-offline/" /> <author> <name>iaiguru</name> </author> <category term="Docker" /> <summary>Deployed System Environment OS: Windows 10 (19045.2364, KB5021233 up) Internet: Fully Offline (Can only be built through package installation.) Docker: Docker Desktop 4.27.2(137060) WSL: 2.1.4 up (Manual installation) To Using Windows Docker: No need to install Ubuntu (unnecessary). No need to use Hyper-V (deprecated in the new version). Using Linux Containers on Windows. Step 1: ...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>17-lessons-about-human-nature</title><link href="/posts/17-lessons-about-human-nature/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="17-lessons-about-human-nature" /><published>2024-10-08T07:33:54-04:00</published> <updated>2024-10-08T07:33:54-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/17-lessons-about-human-nature/</id> <content src="/posts/17-lessons-about-human-nature/" /> <author> <name>iaiguru</name> </author> <category term="Human" /> <summary>17 Raw Lessons About Human Nature Small Gains and Momentum: Small improvements, whether in business, personal habits, or relationships, create a sense of momentum. This psychological feeling of progress is a powerful driver of motivation and long-term success. Sweat the Small Stuff: Small, consistent actions and decisions compound over time, both positively and negatively. Ma...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>AI Training vs Inference</title><link href="/posts/ai-training-inference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="AI Training vs Inference" /><published>2024-09-09T01:39:16-04:00</published> <updated>2024-09-09T01:39:16-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/ai-training-inference/</id> <content src="/posts/ai-training-inference/" /> <author> <name>iaiguru</name> </author> <category term="AI" /> <category term="Basics" /> <summary>The AI market is increasingly divided into two primary segments: training and inference. Understanding these segments is crucial for grasping the dynamics of AI development and deployment. Training vs. Inference Training Definition: Training is the process of creating AI models by feeding them large datasets. This involves teaching the model to recognize patterns and make predictions based...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>QLoRA - How to Fine tune an LLM on a Single GPU</title><link href="/posts/qlora-fine-tuning-on-a-single-gpu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="QLoRA - How to Fine tune an LLM on a Single GPU" /><published>2024-09-07T07:17:21-04:00</published> <updated>2024-09-07T07:17:21-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/qlora-fine-tuning-on-a-single-gpu/</id> <content src="/posts/qlora-fine-tuning-on-a-single-gpu/" /> <author> <name>iaiguru</name> </author> <category term="AI" /> <category term="LLM" /> <summary>(00:00) fine-tuning is when we take an existing model and tweak it for a particular use case although this is a simple idea applying it to large language models isn’t always straightforward the key challenge is that large language models are very computationally expensive which means fine-tuning them in a standard way is not something you can do on a typical computer or laptop in this video I’m...</summary> </entry> <entry><title>3 Ways to Build your Own LLMs</title><link href="/posts/3-ways-build-own-llms/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3 Ways to Build your Own LLMs" /><published>2024-09-07T07:10:25-04:00</published> <updated>2024-09-07T07:10:25-04:00</updated> <id>/posts/3-ways-build-own-llms/</id> <content src="/posts/3-ways-build-own-llms/" /> <author> <name>iaiguru</name> </author> <category term="AI" /> <category term="LLM" /> <summary>(00:00) one of the most common asks I get from clients is how do I build a custom AI chatbot well a few months ago this was something you needed to hire a consultant for today that’s not necessarily the case in this video I’ll walk through three ways to make a custom AI assistant using a few new releases from open AI I’ll review a no code solution via their new gpts feature a python solution vi...</summary> </entry> </feed>
